medicarelearningnetworklms.com 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to the MedicareNavigators.com web site (“Medicare Navigators”), which is privately owned and operated. 

Medicare Navigators contains links to other sites. Once you enter another Web site (whether through an advertisement, service, or content link), be aware that Medicare Navigators is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every Web site that you visit through a link or advertisement on Medicare Navigators.

## Information Collection & Use

### Application Forms

If you apply for a product or service requiring financial information on our site, we require that you provide certain personally identifiable information, including your name, address, phone number and credit card number. This information is necessary to process your application and to contact you.

### Surveys or Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company will be prohibited from using our users’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

## Communications from the Site

### Special Offers and Updates

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals and promotions. You can sign up for these emails from us on our registration page.

Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out.”

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section.

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. You may opt-out of these communications. Please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

### Supplementation of Information

In order to provide you certain services, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submitted to us with information from third party sources.

To enhance our ability to tailor this Site to an individual’s preference, we may combine information about the purchasing habits of users with similar information from our business partners to create a personalized user profile. When a user makes a purchase from one of our business partners, the business partner will collect and share that purchase information with us so we can tailor this Site to our users’ preferences.

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

Medicare Navigators may provide Aggregate Demographic Information to third parties. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of our website and the activities they conduct while on our site. We might also inform a pharmaceutical company (that may or may not be an advertiser on our site) that “22% of our users live in the mid-west” or that “17% of are users are using 2 or more medications.” Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this Aggregate Information. We require parties with whom we share Aggregate Information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable, such as by combining it with other databases.

### Personally identifiable information

Medicare Navigators site unless otherwise stated or unless you choose to provide this information to us. However, Medicare Navigators does collect personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

### Service Providers

We use other third parties to provide tools like our Part D Medicare Plan Comparison Tool. This service is offered through our partner Destination Rx on our site. When you sign up for Medicare Part D Plan, or Medicare Advantage Plan, we will share information as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

### Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site

## Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication.

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

## Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address of the domain from which you access the Internet, either your individual address or the proxy provided by Your Internet Service Provider (ISP).
  * Date and time you access our site.
  * Pages you view (recorded by the text and graphics files that compose that page).
  * Web address of the site from which you linked directly to our site.
  * Browser version and operating system of the computer you are using.
  * Medicare Navigators is the sole owner of the information collected on MedicareNavigators.com.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We use a third-party tracking service that uses cookies and log files to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. See “Third Party Advertisers.”

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Medicare Navigators only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. See the “Third Party Advertisers” section.

## Third Party Advertisers

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites to provide advertisements and services that may be of interest to you. We share Web site usage information about users with reputable third party companies for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site.

These third party network advertisers, along with other advertisers and sponsors on the Web site, may use cookies, web beacons (also called single pixel gifs or action tags) or similar technologies (and, in the case of cookies, access them on your computer if you choose to have cookies enabled in your browser) to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicated advertisements. In doing so, the provider collects non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed and other clickstream data. The use of third party cookies, web beacons and similar technologies by these ad network providers is governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

## Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Medicare Navigators. Please be aware that we, Medicare Navigators, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

## Channel Partners, Sponsored or Co-branded sites

Medicare Navigators allows other companies to make services and/or content available to you, sometimes on a Channel Partner, sponsored or co-branded basis “Channel Partner”. To access the services on a Channel Partner, sponsored or co-branded site, you may have to complete an online registration form in addition to the registration you completed for us. These Channel Partners include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content for the operation and maintenance of our site. Channel Partners sometimes have access to your personal information in the course of assisting in operating our business and providing products or services to you.

Some of these relationships may be with companies that co-brand portions of their site and services, or that provide services to you on our behalf. Co-branded sites may have their own privacy policies posted on their sites. If you visit a co-branded site, please read the privacy policy that is posted on that site. Access to your personal information by these Channel Partners is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function. Channel Partners have an obligation under their contracts with us to keep your information confidential and to comply with our privacy and security policies.

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us.

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

  * Privacy Policy
  * FTC Disclosure
  * Contact
